Finding Aid for the Frances M. Crater Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Frances M. Crater Papers
2009
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0655
8.75 linear feet
Biographical Note
Frances Mae Kubitz Crater was born July 12, 1941. She graduated in 1963 from the College of William and Mary (A.B) with a major in Greek language and history. In 1974 she received a Master of Management degree from the Owen Graduate School of Management at Vanderbilt University. Throughout her school career she was an advocate for women’s rights, an avocation she carried into her adulthood with her participation in organizations that worked for equality.
From 1969 until 1974 she worked for NOW, a civil rights organization dedicated to bringing women into the mainstream of society. She founded the Nashville Chapter of NOW in 1971, published the monthly newsletter, served as public spokesperson, and held responsibilities for lobbying the State Legislature for ratification of the Equal Rights Amendment. These papers contain materials on NOW Nashville’s creation and document Crater’s important and dedicated longtime participation in the group.
Fran Crater’s professional life has included being a mental health administrator, Director of Disability Determination Services (DDS) for the state of Tennessee, and more recently a grant writing consultant and coordinator for Centerstone Community Mental Health Centers in Nashville. She is married and has two children.
Scope and Content Note
Most of these papers are records of Fran Crater’s work with the women’s movement in the first half of the 1970’s when the growth of the National Organization for Women (NOW) was countrywide, and when the work for the passage of the Equal Rights Amendment was a major movement throughout the United States. Fran Crater, along with her mother-in-law Flora Trimmer Crater, whose work is also represented in these papers, were important organizers in the women’s movement and in NOW and ERA.
The papers measure 6.96 linear feet and comprise 5 series:
I. Correspondence
II. Personal and Biographical – information about Fran Crater and with information on the work and political career of her mother-in-law Flora Crater
III.Writings - student papers by Fran Crater and with articles and papers by others
IV. Subject Files - Abortion, Employment, ERA, NOW, and others. These files contain newspaper articles, correspondence, and general information
V. Publications –NOW Newsletters from Nashville and other chapters, and many other newsletters, newspapers, and government publications that came out of the Women’s movement.
In addition Box 16 is a small collection of memorabilia.
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing - Letters, March 17, 1973; February 24, 1974; March 17, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Employment (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ERA, 1970 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Legislators and Congressional leaders (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Tennessee chapters, Oct. 6, 1971 - March 8, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee NOW (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National and Nashville NOW, 1970 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National NOW, 1971 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Other correspondence (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Personal and Biographical
  - Resumes of Fran Crater (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - “Don’t Make Mother a Scapegoat” letter to the Tennessean by Fran Crater and accompanying letter (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper article “ Graduate Student Picked NOW Leader” and Vanderbilt Calendar, Dec. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - E-mails re: Fran Crater and the Veterans of Feminist America (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) - campaign materials, bumper stickers, other - 1973 campaign for Lt. Governor, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) - Newspaper articles from her campaign in 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) “ The Flora Crater Campaign for Lt. Governor of Virginia” in The Woman Activist, September 1973 and other campaign materials (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) The Woman Activist campaign Handbook, August 26, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) The Woman Activist: an Action Bulletin for Women’s Rights, vol. 3, no. 9, September 1973; Flora Crater, ed. consultant (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) - “Crater for Lieutenant Governor of Virginia, brochures (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) - Independent Candidate for Lieutenant Governor of Virginia (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) Statements by Flora Crater, May 1973 - October 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Political Career of Flora Crater (mother-in-law) - Sample ballot, General election, November 6, 1973, Flora Crater for Lieutenant Governor (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Writings - Fran Crater
  - “Managerial Questions about Sex Discrimination in Employment”, Nov. 20, 1973, papers for problems in Management III (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - “Public Management Practices: Affirmative Action for Women”, Feb. 26, 1974 (for Dr. Barbara Greene) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - “An Analysis of Urbanization”, April 7, 1974, prepared for Urban Management Module (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - “Sex Discrimination and Affirmative Action”, April 16, 1974 (20 pages) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Writings by Others
  - Beach, Diana Lee, reprint of “What’s in a Name?”, January 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gillenwater, Anne (Chairperson TN Commission on Status of Women) “Discrimination of Women as Viewed by Tennessee Women’s Organizations”, August 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Henley, Nancy “Facing Down the Man” (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hernadez, Aileen C. “The Preening of America” in Star News, Pasadena, California 1971; “Revolution: From the Doll’s House to the White House!” Keynote Address to NOW – Los Angeles, California, September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Janeway, Elizabeth “Happiness and the Right to Choose”; “Breaking the Age Barrier” (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Kempton, Sally review of The Female Eunuch by Germaine Greer in The New York Times Book Review, April 25, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Markoff, Helene S. “Signposts of Success” reprinted from The Bureaucrat, Fall, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - “The Federal Women’s Program” reprinted from Public Administration Review, March/April 1972, Vol. xxxii, no.2 with other materials (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Montagu, Ashley “The National Superiority of Women” in The Saturday Review, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Rossi, Alice S. “Job Discrimination and What Women Can Do About It” (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Syfers, Judy “I Want a Wife” (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Tornabene, Lyn “The Liberation of Betty Friedan” in McCalls, May 1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Subject Files - Abortion
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Actions (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Profiles – Votes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Groups supporting and against (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nashville Services and Actions (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Subject Files - Employment
  - The Arts - “ Nancy Hanks”; “Lights!Camera! Women!”; “Is Women’s Lib Coming to the Philharmonic?” (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - AT and T (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Compliance and Enforcement (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Education, Work, and Earnings of Women (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - EEOC - Bona Fide Occupational Qualification (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - EEOC in Tennessee at Vanderbilt University (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - EEOC - Equal Employment Legislation before Congress, EEOC of 1971; Enforcement Power - Williams’ Bill - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - EEOC - Letter outlining mission of EEOC, June 28, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - EEOC Complaint (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - EEOC Complaints, 1972; 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - EEOC - Charge of discrimination and related papers (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - F.E.W. (Federally Employed Women ) - Music City Chapter (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General Mills (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Labor Unions (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - OFCC (Office of Federal Contract Compliance ) “Employment Discrimination by Federal Contractors”; Olivetti (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Salvation Army (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sex Discrimination and Employment Practices - T.G. I. Friday’s Restaurant, Elliston Place, Nashville, Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sex Segregated Help - Wanted Ads - Correspondence and other papers, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 - P.L.88 -352 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor - Affirmative Action Programs (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor - Equal Pay Act (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor - Facts and Information - Facts about Women’s Absenteeism and Labor Turnover and other papers (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor - Fair Labor Standards Act; Women’s Bureau - Publications (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper and Magazine articles about women working (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper and Magazine articles about women working (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper and Magazine articles about women working (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper and Magazine articles about women working (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Subject Files - ERA
- Contents of Fran Crater’s Notebook, May 1974
  - Notebook, May 1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Equal Rights Amendment and Its Impact on Government - paper by Frances Crater, April 29, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Notebook, May 1974 - Rescission and Legal Authority Papers (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Notebook, May 1974 - 1974 Dates and Events, 88 General Assembly State of Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Subject Files - ERA
  - Notebook, May 1974 (Sections 1 - 7) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, May 1974 (Sections 8 - 16) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, May 1974 (Sections 17- 20) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, May 1974 (1974 Public Effect) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, May 1974, 1973 Newspapers and other materials (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, May 1974, 1972 Newspapers and other materials (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, May 1974, Passage by Congress, 1967 - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, May 1974 - ERA - Pro (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, May 1974 - ERA - Opposition (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, May 1974 - “Impact Study of the Equal Rights Amendment” Subject: The Arizona Constitution and Statutes by Charlene M. Taylor and Stuart Herzog (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, May 1974 - Poster (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Articles - “What You Should Know About the ERA” by Claire Safran in Redbook, June 1973; “Here’s How” by Gayle White, March 1974; “The Working Woman” November 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bayh, Senator Birch - Statement in Bayh Lines from Washington (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Church and ERA (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Crater, Flora - “How Equal Rights Passed Senate - Crater’s Raiders” in Sunday Star, March 26, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Equal Rights Amendment - Senator Ervin’s Minority Report and the Yale Law Journal by Citizen’s Advisory Council on the Status of Women (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Griffiths, Representative Martha - Statements and other papers (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Koontz, Elizabeth Duncan - Statement in the U.S. Congressional Record, June 7, 1972; Sesler, William G. - Statement on ERA October 24, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Information Kit Index, Texts of ERA - a comparison (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Information - ERA and the Draft; Joint Religious Statement on ERA; Resolutions in Congress since 1923; Questions; Source Material; Best Kept Secret of the 20th Century; the Double Standard in Insurance (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Information papers (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Information brochures (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - League of Women Voters of Virginia - ERA in Virginia, 1974 summary (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Map of Ratifying States as of, December 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Ratification by States (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Subject files - ERA
  - Rescission (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rescission, 1973 - statement submitted to Tennessee Legislature (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Resolutions (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Support and Opposition (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Tennessee Coalition, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee Coalition (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Tennessee Coalition (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - “The Equal Rights Amendment and the Tennessee Code” (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee - Petitions (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee Alert Letter ( to Governor Dunn) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Tennessee Alert Letter to Legislators (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Congresssional Record, Vol. 117, no. 6, January 28, 1971; Vol. 118, no. 44, March 22, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Votes by Congress (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Subject files - NOW
  - Nashville - Agendas (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Nashville - Board Meeting Minutes, 1976 Notebook (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Nashville Chapter - implementing By-Laws (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Nashville - Information brochure (multiple copies) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Nashville - Information brochure - Invitation to meet Wilma Scott Heide, Feb. 1-2, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Nashville - Invitation letter; contribution letter, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nashville - Membership list (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Nashville - Membership lists (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Nashville - Membership lists - cards (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Nashville - Membership lists - cards (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Nashville - Membership and general information (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Nashville - Membership and general information (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Nashville - Membership and general information (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Nashville - “The President’s Page” (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Nashville - Statements and press releases (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Subject files - NOW
  - Addresses - Political and Congresssional (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Addresses - Membership rolls (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Archives (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - By-laws and proposed by-laws changes (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chapters - Structure Plans (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Film and slide shows (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Financial information - budgets (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jaycees (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Legal Defense and Education Fund (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Legal Defense and Education Fund (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Legal Defense and Education Fund “Equal Justice for Women” information brochure (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Legislative Alert and other information (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Legislative Office Report, November 1974 and related information (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Legislative Office Reports, Washington, D.C. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Legislative Task Force for States (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Litigation Policy (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Membership Application (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Political Action Research Congressional Profile Booklets (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Public Relations Task Force and related papers (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Revenue Sharing (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Resolutions - National Convention, 1973 - “Prostitution” Workshop Resolutions (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Resolutions - National Convention September 1974 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Southern Region - Addresses (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Southern Regional Area Councils, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Southern Regional (News, By-Laws, Guidelines, Resolutions, political resume of Judy Lightfoot, NOW Southern Regional Director) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Southern Regional NOW Conference Resolutions, October 20, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Southern Regional Board Meeting – Nashville - January 1972 - Photographs from the Regional Meet, January 22, 1972 (dates but no identifications) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Southern Regional Board Meeting - Nashville, January 1972 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Statement of Purpose (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - “Your NOW Dollar”, December 5, 1970 Report (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Information brochure “Accomplishments” (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Information brochures (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Information brochures (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - General information papers (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - General information papers - ideas (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - “Why Feminists Want Child Care” (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Women’s Advocate Corps; Enforcement Report (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - National Action Resolutions, 4th Annual Conference, March 2 - 22, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Subject Files - NOW
  - Resolutions - Individual and Chapter (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 6th National Conference - Washington, D.C., February 17-19, 1973 - Conference materials (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes from Board Meeting, Boston, Massachusetts, Aug. 3 - 4, 1974 and other papers (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 - Conference materials (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 - Conference materials (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 - Conference materials (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 - Conference materials (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 - Conference materials - proposed By-Laws changes; Report of Finance Vice-President (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 - Proposed Resolutions (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 7th National Conference - Houston, Texas, May 25 - 27, 1974 – Minutes (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Pre-Board Meeting (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee Meeting (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Chronological Summary of NOW Board Decisions (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - National Board Minutes (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles, California, September 1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Washington, D.C., February 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Chicago, Illinois, April 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco, California, July 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - St. Louis, Missouri, November 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Washington, D.C., February 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Task Force Communications, January 1972 - October 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1971 ( Agendas, Meetings, Correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1972 (Agendas, Meetings, Correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1973 (Agendas, Meetings, Correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1974 (Agendas, Meetings, Correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - National Office - Letterhead Stationery (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Other Subject Files
  - Addresses, Agencies, Women’s Issues (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Addresses - State Legislators; 87th General Assembly of the State of Tennessee (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Addresses - Toy Manufacturers (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - American Civil Liberties Union - Middle Tennessee (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bibliography - The Women’s Guide to Books (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Bibliography - Women’s Resource Materials (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Birthright of Nashville (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Congress to Unite Women - New York, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Coordinating Committee on Legislative Concerns, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Coordinating Committee on Legislative Concerns, 1973 - Newsletters, By-Laws, other materials (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Credit Discrimination (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Other Subject Files
  - Day Care - Newspaper articles and other papers (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Decide ‘74 - Local revenue sharing (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Democratic State Convention, Tennessee, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Party - “The Democratic Party in Tennessee- An Historical Analysis” by Martha Ragland, Feb. 20, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Discrimination in Education (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Equal Credit Opportunity Act (Senator William Brock of Tennessee) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fair Housing Opportunity Act (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising Materials (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising Materials - “The Notables” (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Legislation on the Status of Women compiled, October 14, 1975 by Representative Sandra Clark (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - State Legislatures - Lobbying and Task Force (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Lobbying Congress (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lobbying at the State and Local level - materials (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Lobbying at the State and Local level - materials (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Marriage, Divorce, and the Housewife (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Marriage, Divorce, and Property (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - “The Bonnie Plan” - Economic Justice and Equality in Marriage in The Congressional Record, vol. 119, no. 57, April 11, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Mimimum Wage (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Minority Women (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Nashville - Davidson County Metropolitan Council (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Nashville Women’s Center - Collection of Papers (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Nashville Women’s Center - Newsletters and other papers (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Planned Parenthood of Nashville (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - “Rap Groups - The Feminist Connection” by Letty Cottin Pogrebin (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Rape - The Rape Prevention and Crisis Center of Nashville (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Rape Cases (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Republican Party (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Other Subject Files
  - Seminars and Symposia (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Sexuality Questionnaire (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Purpose of the Small Group in the Women’s Movement (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Southern Women’s Conference on Delegate Selection, 1972 (1) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Southern Women’s Conference on Delegate Selection, 1972 (2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Southern Women’s Conference on Delegate Selection, 1972 (3) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sports Discrimination - Newspaper Articles (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Tennessee Commission on the Status of Women - Information materials (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee Commission on the Status of Women - Poster, December 1973 “Women in a Violent Society”; Directory (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee Family Law Act, tentative draft, June 1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Vanderbilt University - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Women’s Studies, Dec. 19, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Vanderbilt University - Symposium - “Choice and Change for Women” materials from the program, October 1973 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Vanderbilt University- Seminars and Symposia (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Volunteer Women’s Round Table - Agenda for Democratic Women, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Volunteer Women’s Round Table - Agenda for Democratic Women, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Volunteer Women’s Round Table - Agenda for Democratic Women, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Volunteer Women’s Round Table - Agenda, 1974, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Women in the Military in U.S. Congressional Record, Jan. 24, 1972, Vol. 118, no. 5; Draft and the ERA (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - “Women in Politics” by Elaine Shannon; Profile of Bonnie Cowan, Candidate for Supreme Court Judge; New York State NOW - “Plunging In: Women in Politics”, September 1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Women’s Rights - information brochures and catalog (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Subject Files - Other
  - Women’s Political Caucus, 1972 - collection of papers (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Women’s Political Caucus, 1973 - Newsletters, meeting minutes, articles, statement of purpose and other papers (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Women’s Political Caucus - Nashville, TN, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Women in Poverty and on Welfare (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Women and Religion - Newspaper articles - the Tennessean - “Chaplain Sees Rocky Road in her Air Force Duty”, Dec. 13, 1973; “Jane Fonda to Address Vanderbilt in November” Sept. 21, 1973; “Symposium for Women Opens Today” April 6, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Women and Religion - “ Jesus and the Liberated Woman” by Dr. Billy Graham in Presbyterian Layman, Feb. 1971; “Astra Goddess of Justice and Balance: A Feminist Theology” by Pearl Ross (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Women and Religion - “Pioneering Female Theologians”; “The Sisterhood for Personhood” a newsletter, summer/fall, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Women and Religion - Scarritt College Programs - “What Can a Woman Believe”, April 6 -8, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 8)